// Biology Questions
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: " “Leaves are the food factories of plant”. But, how does cactus (desert plants) carry out photosynthesis?",
    answer: "Stems",
    options: [
      "Roots",
      "Spines",
      "Stems",
      "Green leaves"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "A plant that has both autotrophic and heterotrophic mode Of nutrition.",
    answer: "Pitcher plant",
    options: [
      "Sundari plant",
      "Rhizobium",
      "Amarbel",
      "Pitcher plant"

    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "In photosynthesis process, solar energy is converted into which energy?",
    answer: "Chemical energy",
    options: [
      "Carbohydrate energy",
      "Growth energy",
      "Chemical energy",
      "Physical energy"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "In non-green plants and animals, their mode of nutrition is",
    answer: "Heterotrophic",
    options: [
      "Saprophytic",
      "Parasitic",
      "Heterotrophic",
      "Autotrophic"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following raw materials is available in the air for?",
    answer: "Carbon dioxide",
    options: [
      "Oxygen",
      "Carbon dioxide",
      "Nitrogen",
      "Hydrogen"
    ]
  },
  {
  numb: 6,
  question: "I am white and soft. I grow well in the rainy season. Children pluck me from the ground and admire me. But i absorb nutrients from dead animals and plants”.",
  answer: "Mushroom",
  options: [
    "White Lotus",
    "Mushroom",
    "Pitcher plant",
    "White Marigold"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 7,
  question: "When we observe the lower surface of a leaf through a magnifying lens, we see numerous small openings. Which of the following is the term given to such openings?",
  answer: "Stomata",
  options: [
    "Stomata",
    "Lamina",
    "Mid rib",
    "Veins"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 8,
  question: "Which of the following equations is correct about “photosynthesis”?",
  answer: "Carbon dioxide + Water + (Sunlight and Chlorophyll) → Carbohydrates + Oxygen",
  options: [
    "Carbon dioxide + Water + (Sunlight and Chlorophyll) → Carbohydrates + Ozone",
    "Carbon dioxide + Hydrogen + (Sunlight and Chlorophyll) → Carbohydrates + Oxygen",
    "Nitrogen dioxide + Water + (Sunlight and Chlorophyll) → Carbohydrates + Ozone",
    "Carbon dioxide + Water + (Sunlight and Chlorophyll) → Carbohydrates + Oxygen"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 9,
  question: "Algae and fungi are",
  answer: "Autotroph and Saprotroph",
  options: [
    "Autotroph and Parasite",
    "Heterotroph and Saprotroph",
    "Heterotroph and Parasite",
    "Autotroph and Saprotroph"
  ]
},
  {
  numb: 10,
  question: "Why insectivorous plants trap insects?",
  answer: "They can’t get sufficient nutrients, as nitrogen, from soil.",
  options: [
    "They can’t get sufficient nutrients, as nitrogen, from soil.",
    "They want to take sometimes different nutrition as juices of insects.",
    "They are autotrophs and some autotrophs are not able to make food.",
    "Once in a week, they used their digestive system."
  ]
},

];
